jiu.edu 2015-06-13

# Online Privacy Policy | Jones International University

### Effective Date of This Online Privacy Policy 

This Online Privacy Policy is effective as of October 5, 2006  
(Updated on March 22, 2013) 

### Online Privacy Policy is Part of Our Terms of Use

This Online Privacy Policy is referenced in and an integral part of the Terms of Use governing your use of this website. Please take a few minutes to review our Terms of Use, if you have not already done so.

### Scope and Highlights of This Online Privacy Policy

This Online Privacy Policy describes how Jones International University (“JIU”, “we”, “us” and “our”) protects your privacy when you use the websites that display this Online Privacy Policy (our “Sites”).

This Online Privacy Policy applies only to websites that display this Online Privacy Policy, including the JIU Sites located at the following web addresses: [www.international.edu](http://www.international.edu/) and www.jiu.edu.

This Online Privacy Policy applies only to personal information collected through our Sites. “Personal information” means information that identifies you personally, either alone or in combination with other information available to us.

**IMPORTANT INFORMATION FOR CURRENT AND FORMER STUDENTS:** THIS ONLINE PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT APPLY TO THE PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT CURRENT AND FORMER JIU STUDENTS THAT WE COLLECT ON THE PASSWORD-PROTECTED AREAS OF OUR SITES, FOR EXAMPLE, OUR ONLINE APPLICATION SITE AND OUR COURSE SITES. IF YOU ARE A CURRENT OR FORMER JIU STUDENT, PLEASE REVIEW OUR STUDENT PRIVACY POLICY TO LEARN HOW WE PROTECT THE PRIVACY OF OUR STUDENTS.

To review highlights of this Online Privacy Policy click here.

This Online Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the Terms of Use that govern your use of our Sites. To review the full Terms of Use for these Sites, click here.

### Privacy Notices

This Online Privacy Policy may be supplemented or amended from time to time by “Privacy Notices” posted on our Sites. Our Privacy Notices provide a level of detail that we cannot provide in this more general description of our privacy practices. For example, certain pages of our Sites contain Privacy Notices providing details about the personal information we collect on those pages, why we need that information, and choices you may have about the ways we use that information.

### Your Consent to This Online Privacy Policy

By using a JIU Site that displays this Online Privacy Policy, you are agreeing to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Online Privacy Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you). If you do not consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as described in this Online Privacy Policy (and any Privacy Notices that apply to you), you may not use this Site.

### This Online Privacy Policy May Change

We reserve the right to update or modify this Online Privacy Policy at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of this Online Privacy Policy on the Sites governed by this Online Privacy Policy. These changes will only apply to personal information we collect after we have posted the revised Online Privacy Policy on our Sites. Your use of one of our Sites following any such change constitutes your agreement that all personal information collected from or about you through these Sites after the revised Online Privacy Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Online Privacy Policy.

To alert you to these changes, we will provide a notice at the top of this Online Privacy Policy for at least 30 days after the new effective date and highlight the changes so that you can locate them easily. Unless the change is a minor change (such as a change in our contact information) or a non-substantive change (such as the reformatting of our Online Privacy Policy), we will also post notices on the home pages and/or on the relevant pages of our Sites for 30 days after the new effective date to alert you to the change.

From time-to-time, for example, because of changes in the law or technology or the way we operate our business, we may ask your permission to use the personal information we have collected from you in the past in new or different ways. We will do this by sending you a notice by email or postal mail at the last email or postal address you provided us, asking you to agree to the change. If you do not expressly agree to the change, we may, at our discretion, delete all or some of your personal information from our databases to avoid using your information in ways to which you have not consented.

You may access the current version of this Online Privacy Policy at any time by clicking on the link marked “Privacy Policy” at the bottom of each page of our Sites.

### What Personal Information Do We Collect Through Our Sites?

_Information You Volunteer_. We collect the personal information you knowingly and voluntarily provide when you use one of our Sites, for example, the information you provide when you request information, create an account, submit an application, or contact us with questions or comments.

_Information Sent to Us by Your Web Browser_. We collect information that is sent to us automatically by your web browser. This information typically includes your IP address, the address of the web page you were visiting when you accessed our Site, the name of your operating system (such as Windows® or Macintosh®), the name and version of your browser (such as Firefox® or Internet Explorer®), and the date and time of your visit. The information we receive depends on the settings on your web browser. Please check your browser if you want to learn what information your browser sends or how to change your settings.

The information provided by your browser does not identify you personally. We use this non-personal information primarily to create statistics that help us improve our Sites and make them more compatible with the technology used by our visitors. However, if you have created a user identity on one of your visits to a JIU Site (for example, by creating an account), we may link the information provided by your browser to information that identifies you personally and use it for the purposes described below. In addition, we may review our server logs for security purposes, such as detecting intrusions into our network. If we suspect criminal activity, we might share our server logs -- which contain visitors’ IP addresses -- with the appropriate investigative authorities who could use that information to trace and identify individuals.

_Information Collected Using “Cookies” and Other Web Technologies_. We use “cookies,” and similar technologies to collect information and manage our Sites. A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web server. Cookies cannot be used to install computer programs or deliver viruses to your computer. We may use two types of cookies -- “session cookies” and “persistent cookies.”

_Session Cookies_. A “session cookie” assigns a randomly-generated, unique identification number to your computer when you access one of our Sites. Assigning your computer a number permits us to follow you as you move from page to page. A session cookie expires after you close your browser.

Generally, we use session cookies to collect information about the ways visitors use our Sites – which pages they visit, which links they use, and how long they stay on each page. We analyze this information (known as “click-stream information”) to better understand our visitors’ interests and needs and to improve the content and functionality of our Sites. Session cookies are also used to facilitate the proper functioning of the features of our Sites. For example, session cookies let us follow you as you complete a multi-page application. Without the session cookie, you would have to enter your name on each page of the application.

Sessions cookies do not identify you personally. If, however, you have created a user identity on one of your visits to a JIU Site, we may link the information collected by our session cookies to information that identifies you personally. For example, if you create a user account at [www.jiu.edu](http://www.jiu.edu/), you will be asked to choose a user name and password. You will also be asked to provide your name, email address and other information. The information you provide will be stored in your account. Each time you log in using your user name and password, our server will recognize you. The additional information you provide during subsequent visits may be added to your account information. For example, if you start an application and leave our Site before you have completed it, we will store your partially completed application in your account. The next time you log on, using your user name and password, your application will be waiting for you and you will be able to start again where you left off.

_Persistent Cookies_. If you enroll in JIU, we will place one or more “persistent cookies” on your computer. These persistent cookies will identify you as a student enrolled in one of our programs and may contain other information that will allow us to provide you with a personalized online educational experience. Unlike a “session cookie,” a persistent cookie does not expire when you close your browser. It stays on your computer until it expires (for example, at the end of the academic year) or until you delete it.

In the future, we may assign one or more persistent cookies to each new visitor to each of our Sites. These persistent cookies will not identify you personally. They will simply “tag” your computer so that the next time you visit (or someone using your computer visits), our server will recognize you, not by name, but by the “tag” on your computer. This will enable us to provide you with a personalized experience even if we do not know who you are. It will also allow us to collect more accurate information about the ways people use our Sites, for example, how people use our Site on their first visit and how often they return. If, at some point, you create a user identity, we may link the information collected by these persistent session cookies to information that identifies you personally. This will enable us to augment your account information with information that will help us serve you better. We currently do not have this capability, but if and when we introduce this feature, we will update this Online Privacy Policy and notify you as described above.

If you do not wish to receive cookies, you may set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your computer. You may also delete our cookies as soon as you leave our Site. Although generally you are not required to accept our cookies when you visit our Sites, if you set your browser to reject cookies, you will not be able to use all of the features and functionality of our Sites. For example, you will not be able to use our online application process unless your browser is set to accept cookies.

### How Do We Use Your Personal Information?

JIU uses the personal information collected through JIU Sites to provide the information, services and products you request. For example, if you submit a request for information, we will use your contact information to contact you with information about our programs. Generally, we prefer to contact you by telephone so that we can learn more about your goals and interests and provide exactly the information you need.

If you have created a user identity on one of our Sites, we may use your personal information to display personalized content and advertising when you log in. For example, when you create a user account at [www.jiu.edu](http://www.jiu.edu/), you will be asked to choose a user name and password. Each time you log in using your user name and password our server will recognize you. The information you provide during each visit will be stored in your account. If you start an application and leave our site before you have completed it, we will store your partially completed application in your account. The next time you log on, using your user name and password, your application will be waiting for you and you will be able to start again where you left off.

Unless you have “opted-out,” we will add the contact information you provide to our mailing lists and, from time to time, we may send you information about products and services offered by JIU or our affiliates. We also may send you survey invitations. You may “opt-out” of receiving this information or survey invitations from us at any time. To “opt-out” now, [click here](http://unsubscribe.jiu.edu/). If you receive an email from us and do not wish to receive further email, please click on the “opt-out” link at the bottom of the email.

We may use specific personal information for the purposes identified in a specific Privacy Notice posted on the page or area of our Site where you provided that information.

Finally, we may study the information we collect through our Sites to improve our programs and services, to improve the content, functionality, navigation, and usability of our Sites and to market our programs, services and products. We may remove all of the information that identifies specific individuals and use the rest for historical, statistical or scientific purposes.

### With Whom Do We Share Your Personal Information?

We share personal information collected through our Sites with companies and organizations that perform services on our behalf, for example, companies that provide support services to us (such as data storage and web hosting services) or that help us market our products and services (such as third-party email marketing companies and colleges with whom we have referral relationships). These companies and organizations are required by contract to use the personal information we share with them only to perform services on our behalf and to protect the confidentiality of your personal information.

We may share specific personal information as disclosed in a specific Privacy Notice posted on the page or area of our Site where you provided that information.

There are other limited circumstances in which we may share the personal information in our databases with unrelated third parties. For example, we may disclose the personal information we collect through our Sites when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law or a regulatory requirement or to comply with a subpoena or court order; to prevent or investigate a possible crime, such as fraud or identity theft; to enforce a contract; to protect the rights, property or safety of JIU, our users or others; or to protect your vital interests. We may also disclose personal information when we believe it is necessary to comply with the reporting requirements of accrediting bodies.

Your personal information may be transferred to another company (either an affiliate or an unrelated third party) that has acquired the stock or assets of JIU, one of our affiliates, or one of our operating divisions, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution, or liquidation. If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company’s use of your personal information will still be subject to this Online Privacy Policy, any applicable Privacy Notices, and the privacy preferences you have expressed to us.

We will not share your personal information with our affiliates to use for their own marketing purposes unless we first offer you an opportunity to “opt-out.” We will not share your personal information with unrelated third parties to use for their own marketing purposes without your express “opt-in” consent.

### Your Choices

JIU respects your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose your personal information. We generally ask you to indicate your choices at the time and on the page where you provide your personal information. Depending on the nature of your choices and applicable law, we may also give you ways to change your privacy preferences.

If we provide a means for you to change your privacy preferences, you must give us enough information and a reasonable amount of time to process your request. Your new preferences will only apply prospectively. For example, if you give us permission to share your personal information with our affiliates and later withdraw your permission, you may still receive email from one of our affiliates, if we shared your personal information before you withdrew your permission.

### How Can You Access and Correct Your Personal Information?

We strive to maintain the accuracy and integrity of the personal information in our databases. We provide ways for you to access your personal information as required by applicable law, so that you can correct inaccuracies or update your personal information. For example, if you create an account on our main Site (located at [www.jonesinternational.edu](http://www.jonesinternational.edu/) or [www.jiu.edu](http://www.jiu.edu/)), you may log on at any time and update your profile.

If you cannot access your personal information online, please contact us by postal mail or email using the postal or email address provided below. We will respond to reasonable requests within the time limits established by applicable law or within a reasonable time if no time limit is established by applicable law. For your protection, we may ask you for additional information to verify your identity. In most cases, we will provide the access you request and correct or delete any inaccurate personal information you discover. In some cases, however, we may limit or deny your request if applicable law permits or requires us to do so. We generally do not charge for this service, however, we reserve the right to charge a fee as permitted by applicable law.

> Jones International University®  
> Attention: Privacy Officer   
> 9697 East Mineral Avenue   
> Centennial, Colorado 80112   
> Email address: Contact Form

### How Do We Protect Your Personal Information?

We have industry standard measures in place to protect the security of the personal information we collect through this Site. It is important that you understand, however, that no website or database is completely secure or “hacker proof”. You are also responsible for taking reasonable steps to protect your personal information against unauthorized disclosure or misuse, for example, by protecting your user name and password.

### How Long Do We Retain Your Personal Information?

We keep your personal information only as long as we need it for the purposes for which it was originally collected (or to which you have subsequently consented) or for other legitimate purposes (such as regulatory compliance), or as permitted by applicable law.

### Transfers to Other Countries

JIU is a U.S. corporation headquartered in Centennial, Colorado. Our Sites are currently hosted on servers located within the United States, but the locations of our servers may change from time-to-time. The personal information collected through this Site may be stored on servers located within the United States or in another country.

Different countries have different privacy laws, some of which provide more protection than others. When JIU transfers personal information collected online from the country where it was provided to another country, we do so in compliance with applicable privacy laws. Moreover, no matter where your personal information is collected or stored, if it was collected through our Sites, it will be protected by the terms of this Online Privacy Policy and any Privacy Notices that apply to you.

By accessing our Sites from a country outside the United States, you are consenting to the use and storage of your personal information in the United States or in any other country in which JIU data may be processed.

### Links to Other Websites

Our Sites contain links to other websites operated by JIU and its affiliates. Our Sites also contain links to websites that are owned and operated by unrelated third parties.

This Online Privacy Policy applies only to personal information collected through our Sites (as defined above). It does not apply to personal information collected on any other website operated by JIU, nor to personal information collected on our service providers’ or other third-party websites. When you access other websites through a link on one of our Sites, please take a few minutes to review the terms of use and privacy statement posted on each website you visit.

### Children’s Privacy

Our Sites are not directed at nor targeted to children under the age of 13. We do not use our Sites to knowingly solicit personal information from or market to children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, do not provide us with any personal information. If we learn that someone under 13 has provided personal information to us through this Site, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our databases.

### Governing Law

This Online Privacy Policy and our Privacy Notices are governed by the laws of the State of Colorado, United States of America, without regard to its conflict of law principles.

### Questions Concerning Our Online Privacy Practices

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Online Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us by email using our contact form or write us at Jones International University, 9697 East Mineral Avenue, Centennial, Colorado, 80112, Attention: Privacy Officer.
